<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bookshelf>
    <books>
        <gid>3jsYCwAAQBAJ</gid>
        <isbn>9780316217637</isbn>
        <title>Babylon's Ashes</title>
        <description>&lt;b&gt;The sixth novel in James S. A. Corey's &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; bestselling Expanse series - now a major television series!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A revolution brewing for generations has begun in fire. It will end in blood.&lt;br&gt; The Free Navy - a violent group of Belters in black-market military ships - has crippled the Earth and begun a campaign of piracy and violence among the outer planets. The colony ships heading for the thousand new worlds on the far side of the alien ring gates are easy prey, and no single navy remains strong enough to protect them.&lt;br&gt; James Holden and his crew know the strengths and weaknesses of this new force better than anyone. Outnumbered and outgunned, the embattled remnants of the old political powers call on the &lt;i&gt;Rocinante&lt;/i&gt; for a desperate mission to reach Medina Station at the heart of the gate network. &lt;br&gt; But the new alliances are as flawed as the old, and the struggle for power has only just begun.&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Babylon's Ashes &lt;/i&gt;is a breakneck science fiction adventure following the bestselling &lt;i&gt;Nemesis Games&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Expanse &lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Leviathan Wakes&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Caliban's War&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Abaddon's Gate&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Cibola Burn&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Nemesis Games&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Babylon's Ashes&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Persepolis Rising&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Expanse Short Fiction &lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Butcher of Anderson Station&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Gods of Risk&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Churn&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Vital Abyss&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Strange Dogs&lt;/i&gt;</description>
        <status>READING</status>
        <priority>HIGH</priority>
        <rating>4</rating>
        <publisher>Orbit</publisher>
        <publicationDate>2016-12-06</publicationDate>
        <authors>James S. A. Corey</authors>
        <categories>Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Science Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Space Opera</categories>
        <categories>Action &amp; Adventure</categories>
    </books>
    <books>
        <gid>2SoaDAAAQBAJ</gid>
        <isbn>9780765388896</isbn>
        <title>The Collapsing Empire</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;*2018 HUGO AWARD FINALIST FOR BEST NOVEL CATEGORY*&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;“John Scalzi is the most entertaining, accessible writer working in SF today.” —Joe Hill, author of &lt;i&gt;The Fireman&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;The first novel of a new space-opera sequence set in an all-new universe by the Hugo Award-winning, &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt;-bestselling author of &lt;i&gt;Redshirts &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Old Man's War&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;Our universe is ruled by physics. Faster than light travel is impossible—until the discovery of The Flow, an extradimensional field available at certain points in space-time, which can take us to other planets around other stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riding The Flow, humanity spreads to innumerable other worlds. Earth is forgotten. A new empire arises, the Interdependency, based on the doctrine that no one human outpost can survive without the others. It’s a hedge against interstellar war—and, for the empire’s rulers, a system of control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Flow is eternal—but it’s not static. Just as a river changes course, The Flow changes as well. In rare cases, entire worlds have been cut off from the rest of humanity. When it’s discovered that the &lt;i&gt;entire&lt;/i&gt; Flow is moving, possibly separating all human worlds from one another forever, three individuals—a scientist, a starship captain, and the emperox of the Interdependency—must race against time to discover what, if anything, can be salvaged from an interstellar empire on the brink of collapse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;"Fans of &lt;i&gt;Game of Thrones &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Dune&lt;/i&gt; will enjoy this bawdy, brutal, and brilliant political adventure" —&lt;i&gt;Booklist &lt;/i&gt;on&lt;i&gt; The Collapsing Empire&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;"Political plotting, plenty of snark, puzzle-solving, and a healthy dose of action...Scalzi continues to be almost insufferably good at his brand of fun but think-y sci-fi adventure." —&lt;i&gt;Kirkus Reviews &lt;/i&gt;on &lt;i&gt;The Collapsing Empire&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;“Scalzi is one of the slickest writers that SF has ever produced.” —&lt;i&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/i&gt; on &lt;i&gt;The Human Division&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Interdependency Series&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. &lt;i&gt;The Collapsing Empire&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. &lt;i&gt;The Consuming Fire&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the Publisher's request, this title is being sold without Digital Rights Management Software (DRM) applied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <status>READING</status>
        <priority>LOW</priority>
        <rating>-1</rating>
        <publisher>Tom Doherty Associates</publisher>
        <publicationDate>2017-03-21</publicationDate>
        <authors>John Scalzi</authors>
        <categories>Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Science Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Space Opera</categories>
        <categories>Action &amp; Adventure</categories>
        <categories>Military</categories>
    </books>
    <books>
        <gid>3_bJKlAOecEC</gid>
        <isbn>9780316095839</isbn>
        <title>Consider Phlebas</title>
        <description>"Dazzlingly original." -- Daily Mail&lt;br&gt;"Gripping, touching and funny." -- TLS&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The war raged across the galaxy. Billions had died, billions more were doomed. Moons, planets, the very stars themselves, faced destruction, cold-blooded, brutal, and worse, random. The Idirans fought for their Faith; the Culture for its moral right to exist. Principles were at stake. There could be no surrender. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Within the cosmic conflict, an individual crusade. Deep within a fabled labyrinth on a barren world, a Planet of the Dead proscribed to mortals, lay a fugitive Mind. Both the Culture and the Idirans sought it. It was the fate of Horza, the Changer, and his motley crew of unpredictable mercenaries, human and machine, actually to find it, and with it their own destruction.</description>
        <status>UNREAD</status>
        <priority>NONE</priority>
        <rating>-1</rating>
        <publisher>Orbit</publisher>
        <publicationDate>2009-12-01</publicationDate>
        <authors>Iain M. Banks</authors>
        <categories>Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Science Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Action &amp; Adventure</categories>
        <categories>Space Opera</categories>
        <categories>Hard Science Fiction</categories>
    </books>
    <books>
        <gid>CIj1DAAAQBAJ</gid>
        <isbn>9781405921909</isbn>
        <title>Waking Gods</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;'Reminiscent of &lt;i&gt;The Martian&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;World War Z&lt;/i&gt;' PIERCE BROWN&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A twenty-story-tall metallic figure appears in the middle of Regent's Park. The caretakers at London Zoo notice it first at around 4am. The figure, or robot, bears a great resemblance to the UN robot known as Themis . . . &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Who made Themis?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; It's been ten years since Themis - a giant alien metal robot - was revealed to the world by Dr Rose Franklin. It now stands at the heart of the Earth Defense Corps - in case the makers of Themis return to claim it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Why did they leave it here?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Rose and her team are still seeking answers to Themis's origins when a second and even bigger robot appears in London's Regent's Park. A military response backfires, reducing half the city to bare earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;And what if they come back?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As more robots appear across the world, Rose knows it's a race against time to discover where they've come from, what they want and - most importantly - how to stop them . . .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;'Captivating' BUZZFEED&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;'A sheer blast from start to finish. I haven't had this much fun reading in ages' BLAKE CROUCH&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;'Non-stop action and adventure. In a word: unputdownable' KIRKUS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <status>UNREAD</status>
        <priority>NONE</priority>
        <rating>-1</rating>
        <publisher>Penguin UK</publisher>
        <publicationDate>2017-04-06</publicationDate>
        <authors>Sylvain Neuvel</authors>
        <categories>Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Science Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Action &amp; Adventure</categories>
        <categories>Alien Contact</categories>
        <categories>Apocalyptic &amp; Post-Apocalyptic</categories>
        <categories>Space Exploration</categories>
        <categories>Thrillers</categories>
        <categories>Supernatural</categories>
        <categories>General</categories>
        <categories>Suspense</categories>
    </books>
    <books>
        <gid>ry3GjwEACAAJ</gid>
        <isbn>9780525572664</isbn>
        <title>Artemis</title>
        <description>Jazz Bashara is a criminal. Well, sort of. Life on Artemis, the first and only city on the moon, is tough if you're not a rich tourist or an eccentric billionaire. So smuggling in the occasional harmless bit of contraband barely counts, right? Not when you've got debts to pay and your job as a porter barely covers the rent. Everything changes when Jazz sees the chance to commit the perfect crime, with a reward too lucrative to turn down. But pulling off the impossible is just the start of Jazz's problems, as she learns that she's stepped square into a conspiracy for control of Artemis itself - and that now, her only chance at survival lies in a gambit even more unlikely than the first.</description>
        <status>READ</status>
        <priority>LOW</priority>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <publisher>Random House LCC US</publisher>
        <publicationDate>2017-11-14</publicationDate>
        <authors>Andy Weir</authors>
        <categories>Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Science Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Action &amp; Adventure</categories>
    </books>
    <books>
        <gid>FY_HWAcm10MC</gid>
        <isbn>9780307887450</isbn>
        <title>Ready Player One</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The worldwide bestseller—now a major motion picture directed by Steven Spielberg.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In the year 2045, reality is an ugly place. The only time teenage Wade Watts really feels alive is when he's jacked into the virtual utopia known as the OASIS. Wade's devoted his life to studying the puzzles hidden within this world's digital confines—puzzles that are based on their creator's obsession with the pop culture of decades past and that promise massive power and fortune to whoever can unlock them. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But when Wade stumbles upon the first clue, he finds himself beset by players willing to kill to take this ultimate prize. The race is on, and if Wade's going to survive, he'll have to win—and confront the real world he's always been so desperate to escape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <status>READ</status>
        <priority>MEDIUM</priority>
        <rating>4</rating>
        <publisher>Crown/Archetype</publisher>
        <publicationDate>2011-08-16</publicationDate>
        <authors>Ernest Cline</authors>
        <categories>Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Science Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Action &amp; Adventure</categories>
        <categories>Dystopian</categories>
        <categories>Thrillers</categories>
        <categories>General</categories>
    </books>
    <books>
        <gid>uyr8BAAAQBAJ</gid>
        <isbn>9781784043735</isbn>
        <title>1984</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;George Orwell's dystopian masterpiece, &lt;i&gt;Nineteen Eighty-Four &lt;/i&gt;is perhaps the most pervasively influential book of the twentieth century, making famous Big Brother, newspeak and Room 101.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;'Who controls the past controls the future: who controls the present controls the past'&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <status>READ</status>
        <priority>HIGH</priority>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <publisher>Arcturus Publishing</publisher>
        <publicationDate>2014-01-04</publicationDate>
        <authors>George Orwell</authors>
        <categories>Fiction</categories>
        <categories>Dystopian</categories>
        <categories>Science Fiction</categories>
        <categories>General</categories>
    </books>
</bookshelf>
